A Guide to the Papers of the Virginia Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs, Charlottesville Chapter 1921-1992
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Charlottesville Chapter of the Virginia Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs 1921-1992
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
4340-a, 7234
This collection consists of ca. 5000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited 1976 May 13 and 1963 July 9.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of the Charlottesville chapter contain accounts, annual reports, issues of Blue Ridge Echoes and Federation Notes, minutes and by-laws, correspondence, membership applications and directories, memorabilia, newsclippings and scrapbooks, photographs, programs, reports, treasurer's accounts and reports, printed material from the state, national and international federation, and topical files
Topics include an antique show to benefit Camp Holiday Trails; biennial conventions; sponsorship of a child at the Blue Ridge Industrial School, the Charlottesville 200th Anniversary Commission, civic enterprises and local chapter activities.
Contents List
- Topical
  - Accounts--Miscellaneous 1928, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Annual Report on Governor's Committee 1956 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1936-1963, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Blue Ridge Echoes 1939-1949 (Box 1)
  - Blue Ridge Echoes 1950-1966, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting and Leadership Conference 1988 (Box 2)
  - Bulletins: The Cackle and Club Chat bulletins 1928-1935 (Box 2)
  - Business and Professional Women's Foundation 1958-1960 (Box 2)
  - By-Laws for Charlottesville and Virginia 1927-1955, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville Heritage Antiques Show for the Benefit of Camp Holiday Trails 1973-1977, 1988, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville 200th Anniversary Commission 1962 (Box 2)
  - Civic Service: Assistance for Children in Need 1928-1932 (Box 3)
  - Conventions: First Biennial Convention--Old Dominion Convention, July 6-13, 1931 1930-1931 (Box 3)
  - Conventions: First Biennial Convention--Old Dominion Convention Data--Delegates' Reports--Charlottesville Chapter 1932, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Conventions: Fourth Biennial Convention 1937 (Box 3)
  - Conventions: Fifth Biennial Convention 1939 (Box 3)
  - Conventions: Sixth Biennial Convention 1941 (Box 4)
  - Conventions: Reports and other Records 1928-1961, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence 1927-1957, 8 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence 1958-1966, n.d., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence of Wilma B. Moody, Treasurer, and others 1972-1977, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Economics 1934-1960, printed (Box 5)
  - Education/Vocation 1934-1947 (Box 5)
  - Federation Notes 1952-1962, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Federation Notes 1962-1969, 1988, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Finance n.d. (Box 6)
  - Health n.d. (Box 6)
  - Histories--Virginia Federation and Charlottesville Chapter 1941-1964 (Box 6)
  - Housing 1938, 1952, printed (Box 6)
  - International Affairs 1937-1948 (Box 6)
  - International Relations Portfolio 1937-1945, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Leadership Training Workshop 1984 (Box 7)
  - Legislation 1933-1945, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Legislation--National Federation Day at the General Assembly 1988 (Box 7)
  - Let's Go--Correspondence 1927-1934, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Membership and Dues Record Cards kept by Treasurer 1924-1943, 1967-1986, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Membership Applications and Invites 1960-1976, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Membership Attendance Committee 1928-1930 (Box 7)
  - Membership Directories--Virginia Federation 1941-1963 (Box 7)
  - Membership Directory and Operations Manual 1985-1968 (Box 7)
  - Membership Issues 1927-1942, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Membership Lists--Charlottesville Chapter 1924-1951 (Box 8)
  - Minutes--Charlottesville Chapter 1929-1930 (Box 7)
  - Minutes--Charlottesville Chapter 1965-1972 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous 1941, n.d. (Box 8)
  - National Business Woman 1984,1988 (Box 7)
  - National Convention 1989 (Box 8)
  - National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs 1921-1951, n.d., printed (Box 8)
  - National Matters 1927-1929 (Box 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1929-1966, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings--Virginia and Washington, D. C. 1932-1941 (Box 8)
  - Photographs of Members of the Business and Professional Women's Clubs 1938-1957, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Politics 1940-1962 (Box 8)
  - President's Special 1928 (Box 9)
  - Programs--Annual Conventions 1928-1964 (Box 9)
  - Public Relations and Publicity 1930-1959, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Questionnaires n.d. (Box 9)
  - Reports of Officers and Committees--Miscellaneous 1928-1936, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Songs, Prayers, and Memorial Services 1955,1961, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Southeast Region Chapters 1938-1959 (Box 10)
  - Speeches 1955-1961, n.d. (Box 10)
  - State and Local Meetings 1952-1964 (Box 10)
  - Statements of Club Membership 1971-1977 (Box 10)
  - Treasurer's Guidelines n.d. (Box 10)
  - Treasurer's Miscellaneous 1972-1990, n.d., 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Treasurer's Reports and Financial Statements 1971-1991 (Box 10)
  - Virginia Federation Annual Reports of the Officers and Committee Chairman 1939-1947, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Virginia Federation Board Meeting Minutes 1927-1957, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Virginia Federation District Reports 1949-1963 (Box 11)
  - Yearbooks--Charlottesville 1953-1963 (Box 11)
  - Yearbooks--Mid-West and South 1921-1941 (Box 11)
  - Yearbooks--Virginia 1932-1964 (Box 11)
- Memorabilia
  - F.Weber Company--White Surface Linoleum Block of the Rotunda, University of Virginia, Charlottesville n.d. (Box 12)
  - Engraved Silver Name Plate showing History/B.P.W. Club/Charlottesville/Virginian.d. (Box 12)
- Bound Volumes
  - Minutes of Charlottesville Business and Professional Women's Club 1924-1928, 1941-1966, 4 bound volumes (Box 12)
  - Treasurer's Account Book--Charlottesville Chapter 1938-1952 (Box 12)
  - Membership cards ca. 1924-1963 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1929-1930 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1931-1932 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1934-1935 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1935-1936 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1936-1937 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1940-1941 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1949-1950 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1950-1952 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1954-1955 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1957-1958 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1960-1961 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1962-1963 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1967-1968 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1989-1990 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook [ History Book] 1991-1992 (Box 13)
  - Treasurer's Ledger 1970-1990 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1968-1969 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1970-1971 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook 1988-1989 (Box 13)